<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Words Matter on Tribal Thirst</title>
    <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/categories/Words Matter/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Words Matter on Tribal Thirst</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.tribalthirst.com/categories/Words Matter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A new greeting</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/snippets/greeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/snippets/greeting/</guid>
      <description>How is your soul?
The concept of good morning doesn&amp;rsquo;t cut it anymore. I want to start my interactions with people on a more personal level. &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s up?&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;How&amp;rsquo;s it going?&amp;rdquo; are just so superficial. I am not waiting around to actively listen to their answer which has been conditioned to &amp;ldquo;Fine&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Ok&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;Great!&amp;quot;. But who should I connect with this way? Would it be appropriate at work? The rhetorical question is now &amp;ldquo;If I can&amp;rsquo;t a person with a question like this, what must I do to build up that relationship to experience the joy of sharing life with others?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consistency in an inconsistent time</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/consistency-in-an-inconsistent-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/consistency-in-an-inconsistent-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last few weeks, my daily routine has went out the window. Vacation, unexpected opportunities that require different time commitments,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Content</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/content/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/content/</guid>
      <description>This morning I am not content. I feel I am behind on work, blog posts, and my sleep last night was not peaceful. I am more anxious than satisfied, more restless than at peace. It is this type of morning where I focus to reflect on God&amp;rsquo;s mercies which are new every day. My lack of contentment is self imposed. All my needs are taken care of.
Contentment is easy to find Just make a list and start with the necessities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patience - I need more</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/patience/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/patience/</guid>
      <description>One activity that teaches tremendous patience is fishing. I remember in those wonderful mountain lakes in Montana, my brother would be catching fish every five minutes, while I would sit there getting frustrated and trying to adjust my line. He always caught the biggest fish.
Patience is something that can be learned. Just think back when you were a child. You wanted everything now. Maybe you still do. But as you grew up, you learned to wait for the things that were important to you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Value - Each Person Has Immeasurable Worth</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/value/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/value/</guid>
      <description>One day after my grandma passed away, I was given some old notes that she wrote. I place high value on those writings to the point where they have been photocopied, transcribed, and saved in multiple places. To most people, those papers would be insignificant, but to me they held value. I can almost hear my grandma&amp;rsquo;s voice as I read them from time to time.
Value is the assignment of worth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Know, Understand, and Apply</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/know/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/know/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have asked in several interviews the following question.  On a scale of 1 to 5 how would you rate your knowledge on (fill in the blank topic) and why? A couple of key themes always stand out&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authority Is Given By Others</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/authority/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/authority/</guid>
      <description>A definition of authority is &amp;ldquo;the right to act in a specified way, delegated from one person or organization to another&amp;rdquo;. People are not born with this power. Delegation of authority is necessary to have credibility. I learned this lesson the hard way. I thought I deserved authority because of my position. My early leadership style was one of demands of my subordinates, nothing more than a top down command driven fiasco, which no one respected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thankful - Make a list every day</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/thankful/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/thankful/</guid>
      <description>What am I thankful for? Why am I thankful? Can I be thankful about unpleasant things in my life? How do I show my thankfulness? Here is one idea, make a list of what you are thankful for and update it every day. Here is the start of my thankfulness list:
What I am thankful for (the first five) I am thankful just to be alive today. God&amp;rsquo;s mercies are new every day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apologize</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/apologize/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/apologize/</guid>
      <description>A walk in Grand Coulee. Apologies bring peace
Over the past decade, I have seen a trend for political figures not to apologize at any cost. Everyone makes mistakes. It is impossible not to offend at times. It is easy for words to be taken out of context. So why don&amp;rsquo;t our political leaders apologize when they have obviously wronged an individual or party? It isn&amp;rsquo;t just politicians, but business leaders also.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joy, Joyful, Joyous - Tis the Season</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/joy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/joy/</guid>
      <description>Walking with my family on the beach is joyous for me
A song that starts &amp;ldquo;Joy to the world, the Lord has come&amp;rdquo; rings through the night air from carolers in the coming months. Everyone can picture joy. It is the new father and mother holding their infant. It is the feeling when one is reunited with a loved one, or the climax when a big decision is favorable. I am joyful when I hear my daughter sing or play Minecraft with my son.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excite</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/excite/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/excite/</guid>
      <description>When Steve Ballmer stepped out on stage for his last all company event the place was electric. He knew how to excite the crowd. Emotions were stirred up. People were yelling, stomping, quite a few were crying as he charged the stage. His goal was to tell people about the company he loved and poured his life into. People who lead well figure out how to tap into the emotional well of those that follow them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measure - Spend The Time</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/measure-spend-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/measure-spend-time/</guid>
      <description>When looking up measure in the dictionary, I was struck by one of the core definitions:
reach the required or expected standard; fulfill expectations
Admittedly, most of my work has had ambiguous or ill defined measures. But as I am maturing as a leader, I have started looking for ways to measure what I am doing, either for myself, management, or the company. Here are some lessons I am learning:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mistake - We All Make One or Two</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/mistake/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/mistake/</guid>
      <description>I remember the T-Shirt I got on a family vacation. You know the ones back in the 80&amp;rsquo;s, glitter and rainbow decals. These famous words were transcribed on front:
I thought I made a mistake once, but I was wrong.
Over the years, I used this saying whenever I did make a mistake as a way to brush it off. It was my way of reconciling with incorrectness on my part.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future - Leaders Prepare For The Unknown</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/future-leaders-prepare-unknown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/future-leaders-prepare-unknown/</guid>
      <description>One universal truth, no one knows what the future will be. The brother of Jesus sums it up best (James 4:13-15):
Come now, you who say, “Today or tomorrow we will go into such and such a town and spend a year there and trade and make a profit”— yet you do not know what tomorrow will bring. What is your life? For you are a mist that appears for a little time and then vanishes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shallow - You Know There is a Deep End</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/shallow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/shallow/</guid>
      <description>I am convicted as I write about being shallow. There are so many areas of my life, where skimming the surface wading into the issue ankle deep is comfortable. My contributions in work suffer from superficial dedication to solving the problem. I pretend to listen deeply, but treat all the words as white noise on the outer edge, while getting my thoughts ready for the next rebuttal. I use shallowness to play ignorant or feign a lack of expertise about subjects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fulfillment - Leaders Complete Work</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/fulfillment-leaders-complete-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/fulfillment-leaders-complete-work/</guid>
      <description>I have now been working about 6 hours today. I wish I could say it is for enjoyment, but rather I am trying to fulfill a work commitment. Sometimes it takes extra effort, persevering through frustration, or just time to complete. Fulfillment is that finality of completion, the realization of a achieving a goal, or getting to the end. Leaders take fulfillment very seriously, both for themselves and their subordinates. In order to complete work, here are two key leadership behaviors:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amaze</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/amaze/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/amaze/</guid>
      <description>The dictionary shows the following synonyms for amaze:
Astonish, astound, surprise, stun, stupefy, awe. But beware of the trap. People are often amazed by the superficial, the crowd favorite, the unique, or obscure. We miss out on the truly amazing that many times is mundane, common place, or steady. Great leaders don&amp;rsquo;t work to amaze, but rather to take on the tough issues. There solutions may seem extraordinary, but they are built on blood, sweat, and tears.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be Anxious For Nothing</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/be-anxious-for-nothing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/be-anxious-for-nothing/</guid>
      <description>As I am studying great leadership, I find that most have learned how to overcome being anxious. Their outward appearance is one of a calm demeanor, they have a steady hand, and command with ease the most difficult situations. Being a former military person, I saw how well officers would make decisions with determination, even though lives may have been at stake. Nehemiah always comes to mind as a leader who didn&amp;rsquo;t worry, but sought God&amp;rsquo;s council in his decision making and charged ahead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solitude Isnt About Being Lonely</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/solitude-isnt-lonely/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/solitude-isnt-lonely/</guid>
      <description>When you hear the word solitude, what is the picture that pops into your mind? Is it one of calmness, maybe a lake that is perfectly still, or a person cross-legged with their eyes closed and meditating? The word solitude is defined as &amp;ldquo;a state or situation of being alone.&amp;rdquo; However, it also infers that you are not lonely in this state.
We have all experienced some solitude in our lives.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
