<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>communications on Tribal Thirst</title>
    <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/categories/communications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in communications on Tribal Thirst</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.tribalthirst.com/categories/communications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Commitment</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/commitment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/commitment/</guid>
      <description>Everywhere I look, I see commitments that I have made, commitments, that I have kept, and commitments that I have missed. I am looking at emails, work items, bills, schedules and a myriad of other things with due dates, expectations, and perceptions by others about what I should deliver. The flood of these &amp;ldquo;priorities&amp;rdquo; overwhelms, incapacitates, and prohibits us. How do we wrangle this?
Make the commitment to get to the other side!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new greeting</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/snippets/greeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/snippets/greeting/</guid>
      <description>How is your soul?
The concept of good morning doesn&amp;rsquo;t cut it anymore. I want to start my interactions with people on a more personal level. &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s up?&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;How&amp;rsquo;s it going?&amp;rdquo; are just so superficial. I am not waiting around to actively listen to their answer which has been conditioned to &amp;ldquo;Fine&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Ok&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;Great!&amp;quot;. But who should I connect with this way? Would it be appropriate at work? The rhetorical question is now &amp;ldquo;If I can&amp;rsquo;t a person with a question like this, what must I do to build up that relationship to experience the joy of sharing life with others?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Proper Response</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/a-proper-response/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/a-proper-response/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having the right response to others makes collaboration much easier.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Balance of Self-Promotion</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/balance-self-promotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/balance-self-promotion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The older I get, the less I relish instant gratification, acknowledgement, and self-promotion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Boundaries as Leaders and Employees</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/setting-boundaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/setting-boundaries/</guid>
      <description>Do you know a leader who says yes to everything? Their team just finished a significant and stressful month to get an &amp;ldquo;urgent&amp;rdquo; marketing experience out the door and the leader agreed to deliver something else urgent on a compressed timeline. Where was the boundary between the finish and start of the next project. It never materialized. Take a more concrete example. Do you ever block time off on your calendar to get work done and people just schedule right over that without any care or thought?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Communicate With Myself</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/how-i-communicate-to-myself/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/how-i-communicate-to-myself/</guid>
      <description>Throughout my life, I have heard that it was ok to talk to yourself as long as you didn&amp;rsquo;t answer back. People might think you are crazy or something. Well I must be crazy. Not only to I talk to myself, I can carry on quite a back and forth conversation. I suppose that I could just find Harvey hopping around and have the conversation with him. I might get a totally different perspective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can you understand me?</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/can-you-understand-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/can-you-understand-me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am constantly surrounded by a very diverse group of individuals. I can name 15 differently languages that can be spoken in my work hallway alone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silence can be really loud when there is a problem</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/silence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/silence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There was no update in the last 2 weeks. Just silence, crickets, and an occasional rumor that something was amiss.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Question You Should Ask Before Making A Decision</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/one-question/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/one-question/</guid>
      <description>Spending the time to answer this question before any decision can&#39;t hurt.
When I heard this question asked by Andy Stanley, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t prepared for how much this question would infiltrate my thoughts and decisions. The question is becoming one that I am thinking about each time and saying where appropriate. Are you ready to internalize this question?
Andy Stanley put the question in the form of &amp;ldquo;What would a great leader do?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feedback With Integrity</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/feedback-with-integrity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/feedback-with-integrity/</guid>
      <description>Take feedback and keep moving forward. Apply it where it makes sense
Over the past few days, my inbox has started to fill with requests for feedback from my peers. Interestingly, I don&amp;rsquo;t know if they personally requested it or if it was requested by their manager. Either way, I am encouraged that I may be able to participate in such a valuable exercise.
However, before I share how I provide feedback, let&amp;rsquo;s understand the realities of feedback systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Expectations for Communications Responses</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/communications-responses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/communications-responses/</guid>
      <description>As I have started thinking about the best ways to communicate, I am realizing that most of my communications problems are self-inflicted. One of the biggest areas is how I respond. I very rarely respond to text messages, I may read Facebook feeds every couple of days, I am not consistent on mediums such as twitter, and I am too instantaneous on email.
Last week&#39;s email statistics via Delve Analytics</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Smile is a great conversation starter</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/snippets/smile/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/snippets/smile/</guid>
      <description>When someone smiles at me, I catch myself drawn in and smile back. Frowns, grimaces, or scowls push me away. When I walk down the halls at work, I make a practice of smiling at others. Usually what ensues is a good morning, hello, or how are you doing? Oh by the way, they are smiling back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Provide Context for the Data</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/data-context/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/data-context/</guid>
      <description>Just a bunch of information that makes no sense. Just like many decks I see with charts.
I am often asked to provide charts of data, tables of information, and bullet point lists though the week. I just put together a basic bar chart in Excel (Select your table and hit the F11 key) a few hours ago. Today&amp;rsquo;s topic in communication is making sure that the data meets the context of how it is being used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting Communications</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/meeting-communications/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/meeting-communications/</guid>
      <description>I am glad these guys were at the meeting. Mural on board the Pride of America
As I was reviewing the email for the last time in the day, I received four meeting requests, all with no agenda and ambiguous titles. My initial response was to just decline without any reason. After a hard pause, I decided to be more civilized fashion and at least respond with a couple of questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Non-Verbal Communication Matters</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/non-verbal-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/non-verbal-communication/</guid>
      <description>One day I received feedback after a meeting took place. My manager graciously let me know that my opinions on various topics were well communicated. There was only one problem, I didn&amp;rsquo;t say a word. My body language, facial expressions, and the way I made eye contact with others was truly transparent and exposed for all to see. I constantly have to work in meetings to make sure that my non-verbal cues are appropriate for the time and location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 5 W&#39;s of Giving Feedback</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/the-5-ws-of-giving-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/the-5-ws-of-giving-feedback/</guid>
      <description>Feedback is something that shouldn&#39;t be frosty or cold. It should always be tempered with warmth.
I am a person who is always looking for feedback, constructive criticism, and critique about my life, work, and abilities. This keeps me humble to grow, hungry to learn, and happy when the feedback helps. On the flipside, I am not shy about giving back in these mediums to others. I have distilled some core truths into the 5 W&amp;rsquo;s that must happen for the information one shares to be effective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communicate Your Vision (Updated)</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/communicate-your-vision/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/communicate-your-vision/</guid>
      <description>As with any vision statement, it is a grand view. Horseshoe Canyon in Moab.
When was the last time you looked at the Vision, Mission, and Values of your company? Maybe you have them memorized and they come out in every part of your being. If so quit reading now. For the other 99.9999% of us keep reading as the vision definitely needs focused on.
Dusting off the vision statement Read the most recent company vision statement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Danger in Isolation</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/danger-isolation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/danger-isolation/</guid>
      <description>Some call it JOB SECURITY. Others call protecting intellectual property. Many want to just have the end result perfect before sharing out. There is danger in these ideas and thoughts as they lead to isolationist principles. When we break down isolation in the workplace, many times this is due to self-serving / self-preserving attitudes. Individuals see benefits to this as it provides a perception of worth and security that sometimes is lacking in their jobs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watch Your Tone When Listening</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/watch-tone-listening/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/watch-tone-listening/</guid>
      <description>My face said it all. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t paying attention. How soon can they be finished with their monologue of discontent and discouragement. Lately, I have been observing characteristics of others as they listen or attempt to. Whether it is a meeting or a 1:1 conversation, we all may need to do a little self reflection or at least pretend that someone is recording us. Here are some of the latest visual queues of poor listening that I have seen:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
