<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Christianity on Tribal Thirst</title>
    <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/categories/christianity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Christianity on Tribal Thirst</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.tribalthirst.com/categories/christianity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>We are all given a gift</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/use-the-gift/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/use-the-gift/</guid>
      <description>Father&#39;s day 2010 - MoPop with the two most precious gifts
Have you ever received a gift and never use it? You know which one, I am sure it could be the Bob Ross grilled cheese maker, or the deep pine scented soap with tar for that extra outdoor feeling. Maybe it is the clothes that were 3 sizes too big, or 4 sizes too small. It may be the one created by your child that needs pinned on your sweater.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Count it all joy</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/be-joyful/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/be-joyful/</guid>
      <description>I am always joyous when I see a Hummingbird!
It is coming to the end of the school year for many. It can be a stressful time of tests, new life plans for graduates, figuring out how to manage the family during summer while working full time, etc. It can seem overwhelming, out of control, and hopeless at times. It is in these moments to take a new perspective. Be joyful!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on Be &gt; Do</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/reflections-on-be-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/reflections-on-be-do/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two words, two letters, transformed by time with priceless meanings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One is made manifest by the concrete actions, the other by essence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The right attitude for work</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/the-right-attitude-for-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/the-right-attitude-for-work/</guid>
      <description>It takes the right elements for life to spring forth from work, but the growing pains are worth it
The work we do needs to be washed in the joy and glory of the Lord. Yes, this even applies to washing dishes, making a bed, or taking the dog for a walk. Each email written needs to have grace and empathy, each line of code written or taken away is a moral decision that must be directed by God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parenting</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/parenting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/parenting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last couple of weeks, I have been examining how I have been parenting. I have been watching what others say about how they are parenting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perception - You Are What Other People See</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/snippets/other-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/snippets/other-people/</guid>
      <description>Probably the biggest battle I fight is one of perception with other people. Why is this a battle? Mostly because I let my selfish side take over my actions, instead of being mindful of how my actions affect others. I make excuses about this behavior to appease my ego, pride, and sense of accomplishment. No excuses justify my actions of self-preservation. I need to rely on the Creator to give me grace and mercy when I fail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Outcomes of Fear</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/snippets/fear-outcomes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/snippets/fear-outcomes/</guid>
      <description>Today on a podcast of Design Matters, Seth Godin was talking about the reason so many people are blocked from moving forward is because of fear. I started thinking about the fear in my life and how it is very selfish and created because I want people to have a certain perception of me. Going a little deeper, I believe there actually two outcomes of fear:
Fear of something creates a healthy reverence and respect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convicted to Give More of Yourself</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/convicted/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/convicted/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today has been erratic, my heart was not at ease, and my behaviors and thoughts with each interaction have not been grace and mercy, but rather frustration and contempt. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are the Treasures You Value</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/what-are-the-treasures-you-value/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/what-are-the-treasures-you-value/</guid>
      <description>It is a pretty true statement of what your treasures are, so you heart and mind are. I am personally not one to have lavish goods, however, there are days when I wish for them to be like others, to entertain for selfish reasons, or to just show that I made it. These are all selfish interests.
My Personal Treasures Family. I consider my family a treasure that the Lord has given to me which is precious and that I want to care for diligently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplify:  A Ten Day Recap</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/simplify-ten-day-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/simplify-ten-day-recap/</guid>
      <description>Simplify: To make something easier to do or to understand.
For the last 10 days I have been doing a study on Simplify. The intro starts out with Overscheduled, Exhausted, Overwhelmed? Sound Familiar? At that point, I just knew I had to dig in and see what insights I could gleam off of the study. As each day progressed, I shared my notes with my wife, who in turn shared her wisdom about the study also.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intentional Living, A New Way Of Life</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/intentional-living-a-new-way-of-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/intentional-living-a-new-way-of-life/</guid>
      <description>The dam is a great example of an idea becoming intentional
It is nine o&amp;rsquo;clock tonight on November 1st. About a week ago, I started pondering the idea of writing a blog post a day for the month of November, kind of like a NaNoWriMo challenge. I found other things to do today to not get started. First, I didn&amp;rsquo;t take advantage of my morning and before I knew it, we were on our way to church.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let me tell you about the WORD I know</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/the-word-i-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/the-word-i-know/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear Friend,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to share with you something incredible, something life changing, something mind blowing.  It is the WORD. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Focus Will Bring Great Results</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/focus-great-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/focus-great-results/</guid>
      <description>Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be nice if all you had to say was &amp;ldquo;Focus&amp;rdquo; and everything just fell into place for the rest of the day? Do you feel that your day spins out of control as you get randomized? If you stray from a normal routine, do you frequently feel that something was missed? I have seen that great focus leads to great results.
Short Term Focus Yesterday was a totally randomizing day, constant interruptions combined with a lack of resolve to &amp;ldquo;start&amp;rdquo; anything that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t result in completion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applying the right focus</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/snippets/focus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/snippets/focus/</guid>
      <description>Applying the right focus in each situation will enable a outcome that is pleasing to God. It creates peace and calm instead of complaints and calamity. Remember, others pay the most attention to your actions when you are in tough situations. This week I will work to applying that laser focus to God&amp;rsquo;s will and not my own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Call Is Not Private</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/the-call-is-not-private/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/the-call-is-not-private/</guid>
      <description>I am in hot water with my conscience.
Don&amp;rsquo;t ever think that you are just talking to a single person over Skype, Lync, or other online meeting communications and that the conversation is private. As a matter of fact don&amp;rsquo;t even think that an email is private. I am doing a lot of reflecting on this today, as I participated as a listener in a call without being announced. My conscience bothered me all night and honestly, I didn&amp;rsquo;t measure up to the ethics and morals that I strongly believe in.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
