<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ecclesiastes on Tribal Thirst</title>
    <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/tags/ecclesiastes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ecclesiastes on Tribal Thirst</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.tribalthirst.com/tags/ecclesiastes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The right attitude for work</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/the-right-attitude-for-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/the-right-attitude-for-work/</guid>
      <description>It takes the right elements for life to spring forth from work, but the growing pains are worth it
The work we do needs to be washed in the joy and glory of the Lord. Yes, this even applies to washing dishes, making a bed, or taking the dog for a walk. Each email written needs to have grace and empathy, each line of code written or taken away is a moral decision that must be directed by God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choose Wisdom Over Folly</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/choose-wisdom-over-folly/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/choose-wisdom-over-folly/</guid>
      <description>True wisdom is knowing that we are in God&#39;s hands
Solomon recognized that wisdom is better than folly. One definition of folly is a constructed building that has no purpose but for decoration. What a shame it would be if our lives are only lived for decoration. Let&amp;rsquo;s have our lives to be purposeful. Then I saw that there is more gain in wisdom than in folly, as there is more gain in light than in darkness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Master of none</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/master-of-none/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/master-of-none/</guid>
      <description>It is always amazing how works can become obsolete in a short period of time
I once listened to a podcast that was talking about the pursuit of productivity. The description of the pursuit of productivity by an individual was very like Solomon&amp;rsquo;s pursuit here to find satisfaction and contentment. Neither seemed to be found. Solomon had all the time and resources to chase after contentment. He jumped from the first thing to the second thing, to the next thing all in an attempt to &amp;ldquo;evaluate&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;experiment&amp;rdquo; with the achievement of contentment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Smart or Street Smart</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/book-smart-or-street-smart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/book-smart-or-street-smart/</guid>
      <description>The more I gain Godly wisdom and knowledge, the more my heart breaks. I can understand why Solomon says that life can be an unhappy business when it is in the world. I see every day situations of people striving to understand in their own minds. This world is busy with the noise of self accomplishment, self promotion, and self centeredness. Wisdom is realizing that God is in control. Wisdom is not trying to straighten out the crookedness that has been put there intentionally by God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New is in the details</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/new-is-in-the-details/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/new-is-in-the-details/</guid>
      <description>Something new every day
Every second there are constant stable things in our lives. They are predictable, they are repeatable, they are a known quantity. I can count on these things to happen. Patterns and order are in every minute detail of God&amp;rsquo;s creation.
Is there anything of which it may be said, “See, this is new”?
https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Ecclesiastes%201:4-11&amp;amp;version=NKJV
The true meaning of these verses is what is not said. Not everything is unchanging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living life with purpose - A study in Ecclesiastes</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/living-life-with-purpose/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/living-life-with-purpose/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I believe Ecclesiastes has become my favorite book in the Bible.  There is so much packed into the verses for contemplation, guidance, and just pure wisdom. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
