<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>intentional-living on Tribal Thirst</title>
    <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/categories/intentional-living/</link>
    <description>Recent content in intentional-living on Tribal Thirst</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.tribalthirst.com/categories/intentional-living/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Choose Wisdom Over Folly</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/choose-wisdom-over-folly/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/choose-wisdom-over-folly/</guid>
      <description>True wisdom is knowing that we are in God&#39;s hands
Solomon recognized that wisdom is better than folly. One definition of folly is a constructed building that has no purpose but for decoration. What a shame it would be if our lives are only lived for decoration. Let&amp;rsquo;s have our lives to be purposeful. Then I saw that there is more gain in wisdom than in folly, as there is more gain in light than in darkness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Master of none</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/master-of-none/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/master-of-none/</guid>
      <description>It is always amazing how works can become obsolete in a short period of time
I once listened to a podcast that was talking about the pursuit of productivity. The description of the pursuit of productivity by an individual was very like Solomon&amp;rsquo;s pursuit here to find satisfaction and contentment. Neither seemed to be found. Solomon had all the time and resources to chase after contentment. He jumped from the first thing to the second thing, to the next thing all in an attempt to &amp;ldquo;evaluate&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;experiment&amp;rdquo; with the achievement of contentment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Smart or Street Smart</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/book-smart-or-street-smart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/book-smart-or-street-smart/</guid>
      <description>The more I gain Godly wisdom and knowledge, the more my heart breaks. I can understand why Solomon says that life can be an unhappy business when it is in the world. I see every day situations of people striving to understand in their own minds. This world is busy with the noise of self accomplishment, self promotion, and self centeredness. Wisdom is realizing that God is in control. Wisdom is not trying to straighten out the crookedness that has been put there intentionally by God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New is in the details</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/new-is-in-the-details/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/new-is-in-the-details/</guid>
      <description>Something new every day
Every second there are constant stable things in our lives. They are predictable, they are repeatable, they are a known quantity. I can count on these things to happen. Patterns and order are in every minute detail of God&amp;rsquo;s creation.
Is there anything of which it may be said, “See, this is new”?
https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Ecclesiastes%201:4-11&amp;amp;version=NKJV
The true meaning of these verses is what is not said. Not everything is unchanging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living life with purpose - A study in Ecclesiastes</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/living-life-with-purpose/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/living-life-with-purpose/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I believe Ecclesiastes has become my favorite book in the Bible.  There is so much packed into the verses for contemplation, guidance, and just pure wisdom. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convicted to Give More of Yourself</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/convicted/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/convicted/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today has been erratic, my heart was not at ease, and my behaviors and thoughts with each interaction have not been grace and mercy, but rather frustration and contempt. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being Mindful In Everything You Do</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/mindful/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/mindful/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The apostle Paul couldn&amp;rsquo;t have said it better:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplify:  A Ten Day Recap</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/simplify-ten-day-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/simplify-ten-day-recap/</guid>
      <description>Simplify: To make something easier to do or to understand.
For the last 10 days I have been doing a study on Simplify. The intro starts out with Overscheduled, Exhausted, Overwhelmed? Sound Familiar? At that point, I just knew I had to dig in and see what insights I could gleam off of the study. As each day progressed, I shared my notes with my wife, who in turn shared her wisdom about the study also.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30 Days of Intentional Living - Recap</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/30-days-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/30-days-recap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My thirty days of intentional living posts are finished!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commitment Is It&#39;s Own Reward</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/commitment-is-its-own-reward/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/commitment-is-its-own-reward/</guid>
      <description>Thirty days of writing a blog post series ends with the topic of commitment. I am truly humbled to make it to the finish line. There were a lot of obstacles such as weekends, Thanksgiving break, not feeling well, and mental blocks on what to write about. On a couple of occasions, I had this nagging voice saying &amp;ldquo;you gave it your best shot, so what if you miss a day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Define Success in Everything</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/define-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/define-success/</guid>
      <description>Celebrate when you have defined success. First shot at taking pictures of fireworks, which was a satisfactory outcome!
Over the last two months I have been working on an initiative to bring prioritization and clarity across an organization. I wish I could say I had success defined for this endeavor. Sadly, I didn&amp;rsquo;t crystalize what that would look like. However, all is not lost and it is never too late to take the step back and write down what success will look like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kindness Shouldn&#39;t Be Seasonal</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/kindness-shouldnt-be-seasonal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/kindness-shouldnt-be-seasonal/</guid>
      <description>This is the season I like best, as it tends to bring out the best in everyone. Little random acts of kindness are being done everywhere and by everyone, and I don&amp;rsquo;t think it is an accident. Why would this time of year be any different? It is because we intentionally recognize thankfulness and have a giving heart toward the holidays.
My daughter was kind enough to share Dippin Dots with her brother on a great zoo outing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trust and a Haircut</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/trust-and-a-haircut/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/trust-and-a-haircut/</guid>
      <description>This morning my son and I tried out a barbershop in the neighborhood. From the barber pole outside the door to the old time radio show playing in the background, it truly was authentic. While getting our haircuts, the barber greeted one of his customer&amp;rsquo;s by name and asked how his Thanksgiving was. Customer service was a top priority.
An authentic barber pole and everything. Complete with customer service.
When it came time to pay for the haircut, I got out my wallet and started to hand him my debit card.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Always Be Thankful</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/always-be-thankful/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/always-be-thankful/</guid>
      <description>Today for many people in the US will be about spending time with family, friends, and loved ones. It will be time of food, festivities, and football. It will be about love, gratitude and thankfulness. Traditions are being formed and we actually have a holiday that calls out being thankful.
It is not uncommon to see turkeys in Red Lodge, Montana. This was actually taken on Thanksgiving day a couple of years ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Write, Write, and Then Write Some More</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/write/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/write/</guid>
      <description>It is never to young to start writing. Capturing a memory and ideas is priceless.
As the years add up, the ability to remember has diminished. I didn&amp;rsquo;t think I needed to writing anything down. For me, the ability to retain knowledge, recall facts of a conversation, or remember tidbits of trivia are quickly becoming memories themselves. I used to scoff at the argument that memory fades and items become harder to remember.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Narrate Your Story With Choices</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/narrate-your-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/narrate-your-story/</guid>
      <description>Red Lodge, Montana Boarding House. I always wonder how my great-grandparents lived and what choices they made. It was quite a story.
It was the fourth meeting in as many days and we were still no closer to a solution. In the RACI acrostic, I am the C for consultant. The project was already off the rails, the deadline was coming up. I saw all the signs of the preparatory blame game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Move Toward Your Dream</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/move-toward-your-dream/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/move-toward-your-dream/</guid>
      <description>Ready? Set? Go!
To get to finish, you first need to start! More importantly, keep going!
I look at each day that I get up as a leg in a race that goes on and on. Hopefully each day ends in the dial being moved towards my dream. Some days I make great progress and I feel like I am running on air, some days it is more like pulling myself out of the mud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Procrastination Is The Antidote</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/procrastination-antidote/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/procrastination-antidote/</guid>
      <description>Procrastination. This word embodies many parts of how I conduct my day. Getting started on actual work is hard for me. However, when it is something I believe is valuable, I jump into it with vigor and resolve as long as I can see the end of it. Otherwise, I become apathetic to the very thought of engagement. When I procrastinate on the premium, that is where the problem occurs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Traits I Am Building</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/network-traits-i-am-building/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/network-traits-i-am-building/</guid>
      <description>The railways remind me of one of the most intricate networks that built our country. There is a lot we can learn from the planning that went into it.
My network is personal. I intentionally look for the right people to succeed with me. They are people of integrity, high value, and share in the passions of my heart. The work ahead is embraced with perseverance by these leaders of many and servants of all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choose Necessary Over Uncomfortable</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/choose-necessary-uncomfortable/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/choose-necessary-uncomfortable/</guid>
      <description>Make sure that you watch out for the warning signs of being too comfortable.
I have been wearing eye glasses since I was a kid. They were the thick kind, with prisms and everything. I would break them, throw them, scratch them, and lose them all the time. I learned to compensate without them, one eye becoming weaker, the other more tired as it was being used more. I was never comfortable with wearing glasses early in my life, but now necessity has me wearing progressive bifocals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attracting a Team to Achieve A Dream</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/achieve-a-dream/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/achieve-a-dream/</guid>
      <description>Each of us has a dream. For many of us it is tucked inside our hearts and minds. For others, the dream is at the forefront of their lives. Some have already started working on their dream to make it a reality. The fantastic idea, the futuristic vision, and the passion to solve a need must have a team greater than 1.
It takes a team working together to pull across the finish line</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking Credit is Really Stealing</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/credit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/credit/</guid>
      <description>Teams from over 80 countries competed. No individuals allowed
The project was a smashing success. John went up to receive the award that was given out at the company meeting. The applause was great and people were thrilled with the completion of such a complex project full of intricacies. This is the type of work that brought the company together. However, the people on his team were not cheering, but rather bitter and angry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What do you want to accomplish?</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/accomplish/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/accomplish/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How many times have you heard the statement, &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know where to begin?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Memories For Others</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/create-memories-for-others/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/create-memories-for-others/</guid>
      <description>There are few things more enjoyable than looking back on a specific memory in your life. The one I remember most vividly is when my brother and I would go out and play golf with our grandfather. We rarely swung a club, but were rather foragers in the rough and creeks for lost golf balls. I remember the tin cup my grandfather would break out that we would dip into the creek and the sour ball candy we would get on the third and sixth holes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Abundant Mindset</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/an-abundant-mindset/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/an-abundant-mindset/</guid>
      <description>Some of my favorite books growing up were encyclopedias. I remember looking at the 26 volumes and thinking about how the whole world was captured there. Jump forward 30+ years. Things have sure changed on what information is at our fingertips. But information is not knowledge, and by itself, the value is small. Combine information with our ability to think, understand, and act on it and the world can be changed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doors of Opportunity Await</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/door-of-opportunity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/door-of-opportunity/</guid>
      <description>A joyous day for my daughter. Happy Birthday!
Today is a beautiful day for my daughter. The world is opening a door of opportunity by officially recognizing her as an adult. As a parent, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t be more proud to see the growth and maturity just blossom. I do believe there are few things in life that have such an impact as the recognition of adulthood. Along with the recognition comes a new sense of adventure, a new definition of responsibility, and an acute awareness of independence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Cooperate or Compete</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/to-cooperate-or-compete/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/to-cooperate-or-compete/</guid>
      <description>Think of the cooperation that it took to build this bridge across the water!
We are taught from a young age how to cooperate with others to create a more harmonious environment. We are also taught how to compete with the premise that it will make us better human beings. Cooperation is a behavior that benefits others through working together to achieve something greater. Competition builds the character of an individual for self-growth and gain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pursuit is the True Reward</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/pursuit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/pursuit/</guid>
      <description>When you dream big, everything that pertains to the dream is big.
You will have to make big decisions. You will have to take big risks. You will have big disappointments. You will potentially get the big reward you envisions. Take a little time on the path to accomplish your dream to reflect. Captured in the garden of the Peterhoff Palace in St. Petersburg.
The first 3 bullets describe what will happen if you pursue your dream.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change Happens Constantly</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/change-happens-constantly/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/change-happens-constantly/</guid>
      <description>You don&amp;rsquo;t like your work situation? Is your marriage unsatisfying? Is your life not where you want it to be? What is common about these three questions? You are. Each one of these questions can also have one answer which is &amp;ldquo;Change yourself.&amp;rdquo; By reflecting on all the things that are negative, you may be able to see patterns that are inside you or an element of your life that you would like to change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Will You Invest in Today?</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/who-will-you-invest-in-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/who-will-you-invest-in-today/</guid>
      <description>I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize it for many years, but Robert chose to invest in me. It is now 20+ years later and I still think about how he was feeding me wisdom, knowledge, and instruction about how to live a life with integrity and thankfulness. In the time I spent working for Robert, I believe each encounter was a lesson in life that he wanted to impart. We have lost touch over the years, because I didn&amp;rsquo;t understand the value of his mentorship and friendship.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop Calendar Abuse</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/stop-calendar-abuse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/stop-calendar-abuse/</guid>
      <description>Look&#39;s like a busy month in 1978. original file at https://silverlaughterband.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/1978-07calendar.jpg
Let&amp;rsquo;s start by saying I dislike calendars. They are reminders of all the work that I &amp;ldquo;think&amp;rdquo; I have to do. Until recently. In the past I have been fighting the battle of appointment Monday, where I start the week with a clean slate and by the end of the day on Monday, I have a calendar 80% full of meetings that I don&amp;rsquo;t want to attend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Life is an Artistic Masterpiece</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/your-life-is-an-artistic-masterpiece/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/your-life-is-an-artistic-masterpiece/</guid>
      <description>God has given you all the tools to create your masterpiece. By the choices you have made so far and by the decisions of the future a masterpiece will be produced. It may be a precision sculpture, or an abstract painting, or even an epic that chronicles your life. The cool things about masterpieces is that they are one of a kind and cannot be duplicated. They capture emotion, display truth, and create impressions on those who view your masterpiece.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Purpose with 3 Questions</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/finding-purpose/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/finding-purpose/</guid>
      <description>John Maxwell&amp;rsquo;s 30 day journey has really been a great inspiration for me. This post is actually my reflection on 3 questions he asks us to internalize. The combination of these questions were powerful for me to getting a definition around significance and how to be intentional. I am realizing that I can take charge of being the author of my life only when I become clear in what it is that I am supposed to be doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Think Before Acting</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/think-before-acting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/think-before-acting/</guid>
      <description>One of the most exciting parts of my job tackling tough problems to come up with great solutions. While the journey can be difficult at times, I know that the reward of a job well done outweighs any challenges, risks, or disappointments that will occur along the way. The most valuable lesson I have learned is to think before acting on any decision. Thinking deeply about your upcoming actions prepares you for the twists and turns on the journey to a solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Success For Others Is In Your Control</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/others-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/others-success/</guid>
      <description>We are standing on the shoulders of giants for every success. Each day this reality becomes more clear for me. What is so funny though is the giants we recognize today are just ordinary people doing extraordinary things for others. I know that my success is directly related to those people who give me a boost in the process.
My wife is one of the strongest contributors to my success.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encouragement is contagious</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/encouragement-is-contagious/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/encouragement-is-contagious/</guid>
      <description>Encouragement is a gift that everyone can give. It soothes the soul, lifts up the spirit, and builds confidence to accomplish great things. Words of encouragement and random acts of kindness are actionable ways to show appreciation. Too often, we miss great opportunities to pour a few kind words into someone&amp;rsquo;s life.
I think eulogies are wasted on the dead. It’s the living who need to hear kind words spoken about them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listen Intently, Listen Deeply</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/listen-intently-listen-deeply/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/listen-intently-listen-deeply/</guid>
      <description>Most of you have heard how grown-ups talk in Peanuts movies, &amp;ldquo;Mwahmwahmwah, wah wah mwah&amp;rdquo;. I must confess that on occasions, I hear those same types of sounds when others are talking to me. I am distracted and fail to listen with intention. Other times, I only get the surface of the conversation, but don&amp;rsquo;t listen to the true meaning and diagnose the root message of what the person is really trying to say.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A More Personalized Greeting</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/a-more-personalized-greeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/a-more-personalized-greeting/</guid>
      <description>Welcome board at the Imagine Cup
Monday mornings when you go into work, has one of your coworkers asked: &amp;ldquo;How was your weekend?&amp;rdquo; I know I greet people like this pretty often. However, what I have lately come to realize that this question is just a formality. It is a question said in passing. I don&amp;rsquo;t take the time to listen. The insincerity is front and center and people recognize it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intentional Living, A New Way Of Life</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/intentional-living-a-new-way-of-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/intentional-living-a-new-way-of-life/</guid>
      <description>The dam is a great example of an idea becoming intentional
It is nine o&amp;rsquo;clock tonight on November 1st. About a week ago, I started pondering the idea of writing a blog post a day for the month of November, kind of like a NaNoWriMo challenge. I found other things to do today to not get started. First, I didn&amp;rsquo;t take advantage of my morning and before I knew it, we were on our way to church.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
