<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>valueshare on Tribal Thirst</title>
    <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/categories/valueshare/</link>
    <description>Recent content in valueshare on Tribal Thirst</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.tribalthirst.com/categories/valueshare/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Is there too much noise?</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/snippets/noise/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/snippets/noise/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes in order to get clarity of purpose, you have to figure out how to filter out the noise of life from the information that matters. I think below is a best practice to follow:
Step 1 - Discover what&amp;rsquo;s hidden This may seem counter-intuitive, but it may be important to actually open the floodgates of noise into a centralized bucket of information. I know of projects, where &amp;ldquo;informational&amp;rdquo; data was suppressed only to find out it is really important.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new greeting</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/snippets/greeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/snippets/greeting/</guid>
      <description>How is your soul?
The concept of good morning doesn&amp;rsquo;t cut it anymore. I want to start my interactions with people on a more personal level. &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s up?&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;How&amp;rsquo;s it going?&amp;rdquo; are just so superficial. I am not waiting around to actively listen to their answer which has been conditioned to &amp;ldquo;Fine&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Ok&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;Great!&amp;quot;. But who should I connect with this way? Would it be appropriate at work? The rhetorical question is now &amp;ldquo;If I can&amp;rsquo;t a person with a question like this, what must I do to build up that relationship to experience the joy of sharing life with others?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being Mindful In Everything You Do</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/mindful/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/mindful/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The apostle Paul couldn&amp;rsquo;t have said it better:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop making labels</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/stop-making-labels/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/stop-making-labels/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How we create labels every day:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That &lt;em&gt;marketer&lt;/em&gt; will never understand software development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That developer &lt;em&gt;doesn&amp;rsquo;t do strategy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He doesn&amp;rsquo;t talk in meetings.  It is just his &lt;em&gt;introvert&lt;/em&gt; nature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Her skills assessment shows she has a temper.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are You a Participant or a Volunteer at Your Workplace</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/snippets/participant-volunteer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/snippets/participant-volunteer/</guid>
      <description>There is a 5 part podcast series on building your leadership pipeline that I was listening to this morning on the treadmill. The part I was listening to was about the role people fit into the pipeline. It made me think of where I work and I started bucketing traits of participants in the workplace vs. volunteers.
Participants:
Are just there to do the job at hand. No extra work required.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Purpose Of Feedback</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/defining-purpose/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/defining-purpose/</guid>
      <description>Think of the purpose that this chandelier was made with. Alexandrinsky Theater, St. Petersburg, Russia This was a poem I created a couple of years back around how we shape purpose in our lives. Feedback becomes an essential component. In the last few months, I really have been focused on getting clarity of purpose and have shared a lot of my thoughts to garner feedback. It has been a very healthy and productive exercise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cost of Perfection Is Higher Than You Think</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/value-perfection-higher-think/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/value-perfection-higher-think/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I was in a conversation about the cost of getting a specification to a &amp;ldquo;perfect&amp;rdquo; state. I made a bold statement that most times perfection has too high of a cost and that I just need good enough. After stating that I started to consider what &amp;ldquo;good enough&amp;rdquo; really means.
What is &amp;ldquo;Good Enough&amp;rdquo; Good enough has the appropriate quality that meets the needs of the task. For NASA, it may be down to the micrometer Good enough enables the customer/individual to do the task with a high level of satisfaction that doesn&amp;rsquo;t frustrate them Good enough drives higher throughput Good enough can be iterated on What Perfection Costs Time to market - Perfection may have you missing the train Stress - Perfection always has complications that add tension Strategic thinking - Perfection gets to deep tactical execution which distracts from strategic initiatives Resources Michael Hyatt just posted a fantastic article about &amp;ldquo;Perfectionism&amp;rdquo; that covers a lot of this same theme.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
