<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>miscellaneous on Tribal Thirst</title>
    <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/categories/miscellaneous/</link>
    <description>Recent content in miscellaneous on Tribal Thirst</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.tribalthirst.com/categories/miscellaneous/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A good cup of coffee @ 4 am</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/a-good-cup-of-coffee-4-am/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/a-good-cup-of-coffee-4-am/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;    &lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img style=&#34;width: 80%&#34;   src=&#34;https://www.tribalthirst.com/images/posts/coffee.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Coffee is good any time of the day, not just 4 am&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

Sometimes it is the small things in life delivered at the right time that bring joy. I thought at first it was the cup of coffee I just made, but then realized it is the intricacies of that cup of coffee that God has paid so much attention to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is there too much noise?</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/snippets/noise/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/snippets/noise/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes in order to get clarity of purpose, you have to figure out how to filter out the noise of life from the information that matters. I think below is a best practice to follow:
Step 1 - Discover what&amp;rsquo;s hidden This may seem counter-intuitive, but it may be important to actually open the floodgates of noise into a centralized bucket of information. I know of projects, where &amp;ldquo;informational&amp;rdquo; data was suppressed only to find out it is really important.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are you listening or just hearing?</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/are-you-listening-or-just-hearing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/are-you-listening-or-just-hearing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At four o&amp;rsquo;clock in the morning the world around me sounds very different than 9am. i appreciate the stillness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Civility and Managing Up In A Hot Mess</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/civility-and-managing-up-in-a-hot-mess/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/civility-and-managing-up-in-a-hot-mess/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first train of the day rolled by as I took a brisk walk to the coffee shop.  The podcasts were definitely aligned to stimulate my senses for the day on how to be a better employee in the small things.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dignity on PI day</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/dignity-pi-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/dignity-pi-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dignity for me.  I want to be honored and respected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dignity for your neighbor.  They want to be honored and respected.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Next X Years</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/next-x-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/next-x-years/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am most likely on the second half of my timeline.  I am now feeling an urgency in my step to leave a legacy for others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever it is, I know a few things:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measure - Spend The Time</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/measure-spend-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/measure-spend-time/</guid>
      <description>When looking up measure in the dictionary, I was struck by one of the core definitions:
reach the required or expected standard; fulfill expectations
Admittedly, most of my work has had ambiguous or ill defined measures. But as I am maturing as a leader, I have started looking for ways to measure what I am doing, either for myself, management, or the company. Here are some lessons I am learning:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Valuable Meetings</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/valuable-meetings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/valuable-meetings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Meetings. How many of them can be changed, disregarded, and not even attended? Can one spend their time on more valuable work?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncomfortable</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/uncomfortable/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/uncomfortable/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Being uncomfortable gets my Spidey senses going. It is uncanny how I can see problems with much more clarity. The smallest details become chasms that I need to conquer or cross. Now combine being uncomfortable with new surroundings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weeds and Software</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/weeds-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/weeds-software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Saturday morning weeding has turned into a quick 1 hour endeavor which I share with my wife.  There was one area I neglected for about a month though and figured I would tackle it head on.  As I was digging and pulling, similarities of software that has been neglected started coming to mind.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How is your impact rubbing off?</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/how-is-your-impact-rubbing-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/how-is-your-impact-rubbing-off/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How do I rub off on others?  I had to really think about this question after listening to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.entreleadership.com/podcasts/159-dr-jackie-freibergbe-the-ceo-of&#34;&gt;EntreLeadership podcast&lt;/a&gt; featuring &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.freibergs.com/books/be-a-person-of-impact/&#34;&gt;Dr. Jackie Freiberg&lt;/a&gt; on being a Person of Impact.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Purpose Of Feedback</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/defining-purpose/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/defining-purpose/</guid>
      <description>Think of the purpose that this chandelier was made with. Alexandrinsky Theater, St. Petersburg, Russia This was a poem I created a couple of years back around how we shape purpose in our lives. Feedback becomes an essential component. In the last few months, I really have been focused on getting clarity of purpose and have shared a lot of my thoughts to garner feedback. It has been a very healthy and productive exercise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So You Really Want to Take a Vacation</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/vacation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/vacation/</guid>
      <description>The Christmas holiday season is upon us and people are taking time off to visit friends and family or just taking a well-deserved rest. The last thing that anyone wants on holiday is to be interrupted by work. However, for many of us, the connected world is just too darn connected and people tend to think we are always available. We see the &amp;ldquo;urgent&amp;rdquo; response required email and no matter if we try to put it off, it will nag us until we complete a response.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boundary Management</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/boundary-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/boundary-management/</guid>
      <description>Fences are the ultimate picture of a boundary.
The project was already 1 week behind schedule according to the customer. I tried to find the humor in that assumption since the project was only 1 week old. Couldn&amp;rsquo;t they read the milestones and our current sprint plan? I could hear the voices in my head crafting up the blame game quips and quotes already. I mean really? Do you think the team has just been sitting around?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living a Transformational Life</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/living-a-transformational-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/living-a-transformational-life/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I have tried to take a step back and look at the transformations that are occurring all around me. I am seeing my seventeen year old now as a young adult making choices for herself, that used to be part of our role as parents. At work, I see the decisions of last years organizational shifts starting to solidify. I look in the mirror and see the grey hairs of wisdom where youthful ignorance used to be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work is what you make it - 10 observations</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/work-is-what-you-make-it-10-observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/work-is-what-you-make-it-10-observations/</guid>
      <description>I was really looking forward to a breakfast talk about work and worship in downtown Seattle. The cogs of the work engine were grinding and a pleasant change of pace where I could soak in information was just what I needed. I am glad I wasn&amp;rsquo;t disappointed. Here are 10 key notes in no particular order from that talk:
Very few people ever get to work in what they are truly passionate about.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
