<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Tribal Thirst</title>
    <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Tribal Thirst</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Working with a Veteran</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/veteran/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/veteran/</guid>
      <description>I was on this ship, when the picture was taken in 1992. Courtesy of PHC Robert K. Hemmerly, USN - U.S. DefenseImagery photo VIRIN: DN-SN-95-00815
I am grateful as an 8 year Navy veteran, to have served in the military. Those experiences have shaped many parts of my character and informed my values. In this month, where we are recognizing our veterans, please consider the following:
We may not be formally trained in the jobs we are at.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commitment</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/commitment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/commitment/</guid>
      <description>Everywhere I look, I see commitments that I have made, commitments, that I have kept, and commitments that I have missed. I am looking at emails, work items, bills, schedules and a myriad of other things with due dates, expectations, and perceptions by others about what I should deliver. The flood of these &amp;ldquo;priorities&amp;rdquo; overwhelms, incapacitates, and prohibits us. How do we wrangle this?
Make the commitment to get to the other side!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We are all given a gift</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/use-the-gift/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/use-the-gift/</guid>
      <description>Father&#39;s day 2010 - MoPop with the two most precious gifts
Have you ever received a gift and never use it? You know which one, I am sure it could be the Bob Ross grilled cheese maker, or the deep pine scented soap with tar for that extra outdoor feeling. Maybe it is the clothes that were 3 sizes too big, or 4 sizes too small. It may be the one created by your child that needs pinned on your sweater.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Count it all joy</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/be-joyful/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/be-joyful/</guid>
      <description>I am always joyous when I see a Hummingbird!
It is coming to the end of the school year for many. It can be a stressful time of tests, new life plans for graduates, figuring out how to manage the family during summer while working full time, etc. It can seem overwhelming, out of control, and hopeless at times. It is in these moments to take a new perspective. Be joyful!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Experience Matters</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/a-city-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/a-city-experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;    &lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img style=&#34;width: 80%&#34;   src=&#34;https://www.tribalthirst.com/images/posts/Hong-Kong-Peak.JPG&#34; /&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;I truly was impressed by the density of Hong Kong&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

What? Starbucks didn&amp;rsquo;t open till 8:00am.  How did I survive the mornings until then.  I must say the breakfast sandwiches were much better than the U.S.  The drop of dijon mustard was killer!  Then there was Dim Sum for breakfast.  I did skip the chicken feet (phoenix claws) for that setting.  It was an experience that I will remember for a while.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on Be &gt; Do</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/reflections-on-be-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/reflections-on-be-do/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two words, two letters, transformed by time with priceless meanings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One is made manifest by the concrete actions, the other by essence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Engineers:  the challenge of enough documentation</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/engineers-the-challenge-of-enough-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/engineers-the-challenge-of-enough-documentation/</guid>
      <description>The question: In software engineering practices especially in the areas of Scrum, Agile, or XP, what documentation is necessary to build a quality product?
The debate on documentation feels political. Each side of the spectrum is moving farther away from the center and becoming extreme with documentation practices. Snippets and quotes out of context are not useful to justify whether to document or not. Each stance has created a quality gap in the delivery, maintenance, and innovation of systems today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a startup work routine that matters</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/a-startup-work-routine-that-matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/a-startup-work-routine-that-matters/</guid>
      <description>What is your startup routine?
At 6:40 am on December 23rd, 2021, enough is enough on being overwhelmed in the morning. It is an official holiday at my place of employment, but here I am still pushing out emails, reviewing dashboards, and stressing on the next set of due dates. Why? It is about routines. The explicit work rituals I have set for myself, and the ones where they are set for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A good cup of coffee @ 4 am</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/a-good-cup-of-coffee-4-am/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/a-good-cup-of-coffee-4-am/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;    &lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img style=&#34;width: 80%&#34;   src=&#34;https://www.tribalthirst.com/images/posts/coffee.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Coffee is good any time of the day, not just 4 am&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

Sometimes it is the small things in life delivered at the right time that bring joy. I thought at first it was the cup of coffee I just made, but then realized it is the intricacies of that cup of coffee that God has paid so much attention to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Review - Is everything in the right place?</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/code-review-is-everything-in-the-right-place/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/code-review-is-everything-in-the-right-place/</guid>
      <description>Is your foundation in good shape?
One of the often overlooked parts of a code review is checking out the structure of the underneath repository. I refer to this as the &amp;ldquo;bones&amp;rdquo; or skeleton of the program, application, or service. It is often very easy to overlook a file or folder out of place. The subtle organization of files and folders can be beneficial for software engineers in future work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The right attitude for work</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/the-right-attitude-for-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/the-right-attitude-for-work/</guid>
      <description>It takes the right elements for life to spring forth from work, but the growing pains are worth it
The work we do needs to be washed in the joy and glory of the Lord. Yes, this even applies to washing dishes, making a bed, or taking the dog for a walk. Each email written needs to have grace and empathy, each line of code written or taken away is a moral decision that must be directed by God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choose Wisdom Over Folly</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/choose-wisdom-over-folly/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/choose-wisdom-over-folly/</guid>
      <description>True wisdom is knowing that we are in God&#39;s hands
Solomon recognized that wisdom is better than folly. One definition of folly is a constructed building that has no purpose but for decoration. What a shame it would be if our lives are only lived for decoration. Let&amp;rsquo;s have our lives to be purposeful. Then I saw that there is more gain in wisdom than in folly, as there is more gain in light than in darkness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Master of none</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/master-of-none/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/master-of-none/</guid>
      <description>It is always amazing how works can become obsolete in a short period of time
I once listened to a podcast that was talking about the pursuit of productivity. The description of the pursuit of productivity by an individual was very like Solomon&amp;rsquo;s pursuit here to find satisfaction and contentment. Neither seemed to be found. Solomon had all the time and resources to chase after contentment. He jumped from the first thing to the second thing, to the next thing all in an attempt to &amp;ldquo;evaluate&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;experiment&amp;rdquo; with the achievement of contentment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Smart or Street Smart</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/book-smart-or-street-smart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/book-smart-or-street-smart/</guid>
      <description>The more I gain Godly wisdom and knowledge, the more my heart breaks. I can understand why Solomon says that life can be an unhappy business when it is in the world. I see every day situations of people striving to understand in their own minds. This world is busy with the noise of self accomplishment, self promotion, and self centeredness. Wisdom is realizing that God is in control. Wisdom is not trying to straighten out the crookedness that has been put there intentionally by God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New is in the details</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/new-is-in-the-details/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/new-is-in-the-details/</guid>
      <description>Something new every day
Every second there are constant stable things in our lives. They are predictable, they are repeatable, they are a known quantity. I can count on these things to happen. Patterns and order are in every minute detail of God&amp;rsquo;s creation.
Is there anything of which it may be said, “See, this is new”?
https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Ecclesiastes%201:4-11&amp;amp;version=NKJV
The true meaning of these verses is what is not said. Not everything is unchanging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living life with purpose - A study in Ecclesiastes</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/living-life-with-purpose/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/living-life-with-purpose/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I believe Ecclesiastes has become my favorite book in the Bible.  There is so much packed into the verses for contemplation, guidance, and just pure wisdom. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are you listening or just hearing?</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/are-you-listening-or-just-hearing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/are-you-listening-or-just-hearing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At four o&amp;rsquo;clock in the morning the world around me sounds very different than 9am. i appreciate the stillness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consistency in an inconsistent time</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/consistency-in-an-inconsistent-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/consistency-in-an-inconsistent-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last few weeks, my daily routine has went out the window. Vacation, unexpected opportunities that require different time commitments,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parenting</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/parenting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/parenting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last couple of weeks, I have been examining how I have been parenting. I have been watching what others say about how they are parenting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Civility and Managing Up In A Hot Mess</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/civility-and-managing-up-in-a-hot-mess/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/civility-and-managing-up-in-a-hot-mess/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first train of the day rolled by as I took a brisk walk to the coffee shop.  The podcasts were definitely aligned to stimulate my senses for the day on how to be a better employee in the small things.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dignity on PI day</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/dignity-pi-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/dignity-pi-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dignity for me.  I want to be honored and respected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dignity for your neighbor.  They want to be honored and respected.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Next X Years</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/next-x-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/next-x-years/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am most likely on the second half of my timeline.  I am now feeling an urgency in my step to leave a legacy for others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever it is, I know a few things:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Content</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/content/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/content/</guid>
      <description>This morning I am not content. I feel I am behind on work, blog posts, and my sleep last night was not peaceful. I am more anxious than satisfied, more restless than at peace. It is this type of morning where I focus to reflect on God&amp;rsquo;s mercies which are new every day. My lack of contentment is self imposed. All my needs are taken care of.
Contentment is easy to find Just make a list and start with the necessities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patience - I need more</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/patience/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/patience/</guid>
      <description>One activity that teaches tremendous patience is fishing. I remember in those wonderful mountain lakes in Montana, my brother would be catching fish every five minutes, while I would sit there getting frustrated and trying to adjust my line. He always caught the biggest fish.
Patience is something that can be learned. Just think back when you were a child. You wanted everything now. Maybe you still do. But as you grew up, you learned to wait for the things that were important to you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Value - Each Person Has Immeasurable Worth</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/value/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/value/</guid>
      <description>One day after my grandma passed away, I was given some old notes that she wrote. I place high value on those writings to the point where they have been photocopied, transcribed, and saved in multiple places. To most people, those papers would be insignificant, but to me they held value. I can almost hear my grandma&amp;rsquo;s voice as I read them from time to time.
Value is the assignment of worth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Know, Understand, and Apply</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/know/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/know/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have asked in several interviews the following question.  On a scale of 1 to 5 how would you rate your knowledge on (fill in the blank topic) and why? A couple of key themes always stand out&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authority Is Given By Others</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/authority/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/authority/</guid>
      <description>A definition of authority is &amp;ldquo;the right to act in a specified way, delegated from one person or organization to another&amp;rdquo;. People are not born with this power. Delegation of authority is necessary to have credibility. I learned this lesson the hard way. I thought I deserved authority because of my position. My early leadership style was one of demands of my subordinates, nothing more than a top down command driven fiasco, which no one respected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thankful - Make a list every day</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/thankful/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/thankful/</guid>
      <description>What am I thankful for? Why am I thankful? Can I be thankful about unpleasant things in my life? How do I show my thankfulness? Here is one idea, make a list of what you are thankful for and update it every day. Here is the start of my thankfulness list:
What I am thankful for (the first five) I am thankful just to be alive today. God&amp;rsquo;s mercies are new every day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apologize</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/apologize/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/apologize/</guid>
      <description>A walk in Grand Coulee. Apologies bring peace
Over the past decade, I have seen a trend for political figures not to apologize at any cost. Everyone makes mistakes. It is impossible not to offend at times. It is easy for words to be taken out of context. So why don&amp;rsquo;t our political leaders apologize when they have obviously wronged an individual or party? It isn&amp;rsquo;t just politicians, but business leaders also.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joy, Joyful, Joyous - Tis the Season</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/joy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/joy/</guid>
      <description>Walking with my family on the beach is joyous for me
A song that starts &amp;ldquo;Joy to the world, the Lord has come&amp;rdquo; rings through the night air from carolers in the coming months. Everyone can picture joy. It is the new father and mother holding their infant. It is the feeling when one is reunited with a loved one, or the climax when a big decision is favorable. I am joyful when I hear my daughter sing or play Minecraft with my son.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excite</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/excite/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/excite/</guid>
      <description>When Steve Ballmer stepped out on stage for his last all company event the place was electric. He knew how to excite the crowd. Emotions were stirred up. People were yelling, stomping, quite a few were crying as he charged the stage. His goal was to tell people about the company he loved and poured his life into. People who lead well figure out how to tap into the emotional well of those that follow them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measure - Spend The Time</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/measure-spend-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/measure-spend-time/</guid>
      <description>When looking up measure in the dictionary, I was struck by one of the core definitions:
reach the required or expected standard; fulfill expectations
Admittedly, most of my work has had ambiguous or ill defined measures. But as I am maturing as a leader, I have started looking for ways to measure what I am doing, either for myself, management, or the company. Here are some lessons I am learning:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mistake - We All Make One or Two</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/mistake/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/mistake/</guid>
      <description>I remember the T-Shirt I got on a family vacation. You know the ones back in the 80&amp;rsquo;s, glitter and rainbow decals. These famous words were transcribed on front:
I thought I made a mistake once, but I was wrong.
Over the years, I used this saying whenever I did make a mistake as a way to brush it off. It was my way of reconciling with incorrectness on my part.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future - Leaders Prepare For The Unknown</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/future-leaders-prepare-unknown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/future-leaders-prepare-unknown/</guid>
      <description>One universal truth, no one knows what the future will be. The brother of Jesus sums it up best (James 4:13-15):
Come now, you who say, “Today or tomorrow we will go into such and such a town and spend a year there and trade and make a profit”— yet you do not know what tomorrow will bring. What is your life? For you are a mist that appears for a little time and then vanishes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shallow - You Know There is a Deep End</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/shallow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/shallow/</guid>
      <description>I am convicted as I write about being shallow. There are so many areas of my life, where skimming the surface wading into the issue ankle deep is comfortable. My contributions in work suffer from superficial dedication to solving the problem. I pretend to listen deeply, but treat all the words as white noise on the outer edge, while getting my thoughts ready for the next rebuttal. I use shallowness to play ignorant or feign a lack of expertise about subjects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fulfillment - Leaders Complete Work</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/fulfillment-leaders-complete-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/fulfillment-leaders-complete-work/</guid>
      <description>I have now been working about 6 hours today. I wish I could say it is for enjoyment, but rather I am trying to fulfill a work commitment. Sometimes it takes extra effort, persevering through frustration, or just time to complete. Fulfillment is that finality of completion, the realization of a achieving a goal, or getting to the end. Leaders take fulfillment very seriously, both for themselves and their subordinates. In order to complete work, here are two key leadership behaviors:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amaze</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/amaze/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/amaze/</guid>
      <description>The dictionary shows the following synonyms for amaze:
Astonish, astound, surprise, stun, stupefy, awe. But beware of the trap. People are often amazed by the superficial, the crowd favorite, the unique, or obscure. We miss out on the truly amazing that many times is mundane, common place, or steady. Great leaders don&amp;rsquo;t work to amaze, but rather to take on the tough issues. There solutions may seem extraordinary, but they are built on blood, sweat, and tears.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be Anxious For Nothing</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/be-anxious-for-nothing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/be-anxious-for-nothing/</guid>
      <description>As I am studying great leadership, I find that most have learned how to overcome being anxious. Their outward appearance is one of a calm demeanor, they have a steady hand, and command with ease the most difficult situations. Being a former military person, I saw how well officers would make decisions with determination, even though lives may have been at stake. Nehemiah always comes to mind as a leader who didn&amp;rsquo;t worry, but sought God&amp;rsquo;s council in his decision making and charged ahead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solitude Isnt About Being Lonely</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/solitude-isnt-lonely/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/solitude-isnt-lonely/</guid>
      <description>When you hear the word solitude, what is the picture that pops into your mind? Is it one of calmness, maybe a lake that is perfectly still, or a person cross-legged with their eyes closed and meditating? The word solitude is defined as &amp;ldquo;a state or situation of being alone.&amp;rdquo; However, it also infers that you are not lonely in this state.
We have all experienced some solitude in our lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Valuable Meetings</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/valuable-meetings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/valuable-meetings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Meetings. How many of them can be changed, disregarded, and not even attended? Can one spend their time on more valuable work?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Proper Response</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/a-proper-response/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/a-proper-response/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having the right response to others makes collaboration much easier.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncomfortable</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/uncomfortable/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/uncomfortable/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Being uncomfortable gets my Spidey senses going. It is uncanny how I can see problems with much more clarity. The smallest details become chasms that I need to conquer or cross. Now combine being uncomfortable with new surroundings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weeds and Software</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/weeds-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/weeds-software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Saturday morning weeding has turned into a quick 1 hour endeavor which I share with my wife.  There was one area I neglected for about a month though and figured I would tackle it head on.  As I was digging and pulling, similarities of software that has been neglected started coming to mind.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Balance of Self-Promotion</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/balance-self-promotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/balance-self-promotion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The older I get, the less I relish instant gratification, acknowledgement, and self-promotion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Review Task 1 - What are the Goals?</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/code-review-task-1-goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/code-review-task-1-goals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Code reviews are one of the most important tools that can be used to improve quality and productivity for a development team.  One of the keys to completing a review well is to know what the goals of the review actually are. There are two goals I would ask you to set: Team Goals and Individual Review Goals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Anatomy of a Review in 5 Questions</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/5-questions-reviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/5-questions-reviews/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a few weeks I am going to give a presentation on doing great code reviews. Here is a piece that I wrote 5 years ago that captured the 5 W&amp;rsquo;s. There are a few changes that I felt were appropriate to make as an update. Most importantly, the guidance below doesn&amp;rsquo;t just apply to code reviews, but any review that you may do.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Boundaries as Leaders and Employees</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/setting-boundaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/setting-boundaries/</guid>
      <description>Do you know a leader who says yes to everything? Their team just finished a significant and stressful month to get an &amp;ldquo;urgent&amp;rdquo; marketing experience out the door and the leader agreed to deliver something else urgent on a compressed timeline. Where was the boundary between the finish and start of the next project. It never materialized. Take a more concrete example. Do you ever block time off on your calendar to get work done and people just schedule right over that without any care or thought?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convicted to Give More of Yourself</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/convicted/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/convicted/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today has been erratic, my heart was not at ease, and my behaviors and thoughts with each interaction have not been grace and mercy, but rather frustration and contempt. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are the Treasures You Value</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/what-are-the-treasures-you-value/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/what-are-the-treasures-you-value/</guid>
      <description>It is a pretty true statement of what your treasures are, so you heart and mind are. I am personally not one to have lavish goods, however, there are days when I wish for them to be like others, to entertain for selfish reasons, or to just show that I made it. These are all selfish interests.
My Personal Treasures Family. I consider my family a treasure that the Lord has given to me which is precious and that I want to care for diligently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being Mindful In Everything You Do</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/mindful/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/mindful/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The apostle Paul couldn&amp;rsquo;t have said it better:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How is your impact rubbing off?</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/how-is-your-impact-rubbing-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/how-is-your-impact-rubbing-off/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How do I rub off on others?  I had to really think about this question after listening to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.entreleadership.com/podcasts/159-dr-jackie-freibergbe-the-ceo-of&#34;&gt;EntreLeadership podcast&lt;/a&gt; featuring &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.freibergs.com/books/be-a-person-of-impact/&#34;&gt;Dr. Jackie Freiberg&lt;/a&gt; on being a Person of Impact.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop making labels</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/stop-making-labels/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/stop-making-labels/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How we create labels every day:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That &lt;em&gt;marketer&lt;/em&gt; will never understand software development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That developer &lt;em&gt;doesn&amp;rsquo;t do strategy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He doesn&amp;rsquo;t talk in meetings.  It is just his &lt;em&gt;introvert&lt;/em&gt; nature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Her skills assessment shows she has a temper.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking the first steps</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/taking-first-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/taking-first-steps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have found it extremely difficult to get started on projects that I think are daunting.  It gets even worse when I don&amp;rsquo;t know where to start. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplify:  A Ten Day Recap</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/simplify-ten-day-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/simplify-ten-day-recap/</guid>
      <description>Simplify: To make something easier to do or to understand.
For the last 10 days I have been doing a study on Simplify. The intro starts out with Overscheduled, Exhausted, Overwhelmed? Sound Familiar? At that point, I just knew I had to dig in and see what insights I could gleam off of the study. As each day progressed, I shared my notes with my wife, who in turn shared her wisdom about the study also.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Communicate With Myself</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/how-i-communicate-to-myself/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/how-i-communicate-to-myself/</guid>
      <description>Throughout my life, I have heard that it was ok to talk to yourself as long as you didn&amp;rsquo;t answer back. People might think you are crazy or something. Well I must be crazy. Not only to I talk to myself, I can carry on quite a back and forth conversation. I suppose that I could just find Harvey hopping around and have the conversation with him. I might get a totally different perspective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can you understand me?</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/can-you-understand-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/can-you-understand-me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am constantly surrounded by a very diverse group of individuals. I can name 15 differently languages that can be spoken in my work hallway alone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silence can be really loud when there is a problem</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/silence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/silence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There was no update in the last 2 weeks. Just silence, crickets, and an occasional rumor that something was amiss.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Question You Should Ask Before Making A Decision</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/one-question/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/one-question/</guid>
      <description>Spending the time to answer this question before any decision can&#39;t hurt.
When I heard this question asked by Andy Stanley, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t prepared for how much this question would infiltrate my thoughts and decisions. The question is becoming one that I am thinking about each time and saying where appropriate. Are you ready to internalize this question?
Andy Stanley put the question in the form of &amp;ldquo;What would a great leader do?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feedback With Integrity</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/feedback-with-integrity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/feedback-with-integrity/</guid>
      <description>Take feedback and keep moving forward. Apply it where it makes sense
Over the past few days, my inbox has started to fill with requests for feedback from my peers. Interestingly, I don&amp;rsquo;t know if they personally requested it or if it was requested by their manager. Either way, I am encouraged that I may be able to participate in such a valuable exercise.
However, before I share how I provide feedback, let&amp;rsquo;s understand the realities of feedback systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Current Communications Response Matrix</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/response-matrix/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/response-matrix/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is a current list on how I think when it comes to responding in various communications mediums.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Expectations for Communications Responses</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/communications-responses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/communications-responses/</guid>
      <description>As I have started thinking about the best ways to communicate, I am realizing that most of my communications problems are self-inflicted. One of the biggest areas is how I respond. I very rarely respond to text messages, I may read Facebook feeds every couple of days, I am not consistent on mediums such as twitter, and I am too instantaneous on email.
Last week&#39;s email statistics via Delve Analytics</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Provide Context for the Data</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/data-context/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/data-context/</guid>
      <description>Just a bunch of information that makes no sense. Just like many decks I see with charts.
I am often asked to provide charts of data, tables of information, and bullet point lists though the week. I just put together a basic bar chart in Excel (Select your table and hit the F11 key) a few hours ago. Today&amp;rsquo;s topic in communication is making sure that the data meets the context of how it is being used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting Communications</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/meeting-communications/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/meeting-communications/</guid>
      <description>I am glad these guys were at the meeting. Mural on board the Pride of America
As I was reviewing the email for the last time in the day, I received four meeting requests, all with no agenda and ambiguous titles. My initial response was to just decline without any reason. After a hard pause, I decided to be more civilized fashion and at least respond with a couple of questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Non-Verbal Communication Matters</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/non-verbal-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/non-verbal-communication/</guid>
      <description>One day I received feedback after a meeting took place. My manager graciously let me know that my opinions on various topics were well communicated. There was only one problem, I didn&amp;rsquo;t say a word. My body language, facial expressions, and the way I made eye contact with others was truly transparent and exposed for all to see. I constantly have to work in meetings to make sure that my non-verbal cues are appropriate for the time and location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 5 W&#39;s of Giving Feedback</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/the-5-ws-of-giving-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/the-5-ws-of-giving-feedback/</guid>
      <description>Feedback is something that shouldn&#39;t be frosty or cold. It should always be tempered with warmth.
I am a person who is always looking for feedback, constructive criticism, and critique about my life, work, and abilities. This keeps me humble to grow, hungry to learn, and happy when the feedback helps. On the flipside, I am not shy about giving back in these mediums to others. I have distilled some core truths into the 5 W&amp;rsquo;s that must happen for the information one shares to be effective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Purpose Of Feedback</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/defining-purpose/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/defining-purpose/</guid>
      <description>Think of the purpose that this chandelier was made with. Alexandrinsky Theater, St. Petersburg, Russia This was a poem I created a couple of years back around how we shape purpose in our lives. Feedback becomes an essential component. In the last few months, I really have been focused on getting clarity of purpose and have shared a lot of my thoughts to garner feedback. It has been a very healthy and productive exercise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communicate Your Vision (Updated)</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/communicate-your-vision/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/communicate-your-vision/</guid>
      <description>As with any vision statement, it is a grand view. Horseshoe Canyon in Moab.
When was the last time you looked at the Vision, Mission, and Values of your company? Maybe you have them memorized and they come out in every part of your being. If so quit reading now. For the other 99.9999% of us keep reading as the vision definitely needs focused on.
Dusting off the vision statement Read the most recent company vision statement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding Death Marches On Software Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/avoiding-death-marches-on-software-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/avoiding-death-marches-on-software-projects/</guid>
      <description>The death march towards the release date has begun. The email just went out to ask for &amp;ldquo;volunteers&amp;rdquo; to put in a few extra hours this weekend to complete a couple rounds of testing before sending it over the wall for user testing. The project manager is trying to herd cats to get a complete status before the leadership team goes on &amp;ldquo;holiday&amp;rdquo;. The developers are questioning why leadership isn&amp;rsquo;t going to be in on the weekend and what does volunteer mean anyways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So You Really Want to Take a Vacation</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/vacation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/vacation/</guid>
      <description>The Christmas holiday season is upon us and people are taking time off to visit friends and family or just taking a well-deserved rest. The last thing that anyone wants on holiday is to be interrupted by work. However, for many of us, the connected world is just too darn connected and people tend to think we are always available. We see the &amp;ldquo;urgent&amp;rdquo; response required email and no matter if we try to put it off, it will nag us until we complete a response.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boundary Management</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/boundary-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/boundary-management/</guid>
      <description>Fences are the ultimate picture of a boundary.
The project was already 1 week behind schedule according to the customer. I tried to find the humor in that assumption since the project was only 1 week old. Couldn&amp;rsquo;t they read the milestones and our current sprint plan? I could hear the voices in my head crafting up the blame game quips and quotes already. I mean really? Do you think the team has just been sitting around?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30 Days of Intentional Living - Recap</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/30-days-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/30-days-recap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My thirty days of intentional living posts are finished!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commitment Is It&#39;s Own Reward</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/commitment-is-its-own-reward/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/commitment-is-its-own-reward/</guid>
      <description>Thirty days of writing a blog post series ends with the topic of commitment. I am truly humbled to make it to the finish line. There were a lot of obstacles such as weekends, Thanksgiving break, not feeling well, and mental blocks on what to write about. On a couple of occasions, I had this nagging voice saying &amp;ldquo;you gave it your best shot, so what if you miss a day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Define Success in Everything</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/define-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/define-success/</guid>
      <description>Celebrate when you have defined success. First shot at taking pictures of fireworks, which was a satisfactory outcome!
Over the last two months I have been working on an initiative to bring prioritization and clarity across an organization. I wish I could say I had success defined for this endeavor. Sadly, I didn&amp;rsquo;t crystalize what that would look like. However, all is not lost and it is never too late to take the step back and write down what success will look like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kindness Shouldn&#39;t Be Seasonal</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/kindness-shouldnt-be-seasonal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/kindness-shouldnt-be-seasonal/</guid>
      <description>This is the season I like best, as it tends to bring out the best in everyone. Little random acts of kindness are being done everywhere and by everyone, and I don&amp;rsquo;t think it is an accident. Why would this time of year be any different? It is because we intentionally recognize thankfulness and have a giving heart toward the holidays.
My daughter was kind enough to share Dippin Dots with her brother on a great zoo outing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trust and a Haircut</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/trust-and-a-haircut/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/trust-and-a-haircut/</guid>
      <description>This morning my son and I tried out a barbershop in the neighborhood. From the barber pole outside the door to the old time radio show playing in the background, it truly was authentic. While getting our haircuts, the barber greeted one of his customer&amp;rsquo;s by name and asked how his Thanksgiving was. Customer service was a top priority.
An authentic barber pole and everything. Complete with customer service.
When it came time to pay for the haircut, I got out my wallet and started to hand him my debit card.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Always Be Thankful</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/always-be-thankful/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/always-be-thankful/</guid>
      <description>Today for many people in the US will be about spending time with family, friends, and loved ones. It will be time of food, festivities, and football. It will be about love, gratitude and thankfulness. Traditions are being formed and we actually have a holiday that calls out being thankful.
It is not uncommon to see turkeys in Red Lodge, Montana. This was actually taken on Thanksgiving day a couple of years ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Write, Write, and Then Write Some More</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/write/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/write/</guid>
      <description>It is never to young to start writing. Capturing a memory and ideas is priceless.
As the years add up, the ability to remember has diminished. I didn&amp;rsquo;t think I needed to writing anything down. For me, the ability to retain knowledge, recall facts of a conversation, or remember tidbits of trivia are quickly becoming memories themselves. I used to scoff at the argument that memory fades and items become harder to remember.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Narrate Your Story With Choices</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/narrate-your-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/narrate-your-story/</guid>
      <description>Red Lodge, Montana Boarding House. I always wonder how my great-grandparents lived and what choices they made. It was quite a story.
It was the fourth meeting in as many days and we were still no closer to a solution. In the RACI acrostic, I am the C for consultant. The project was already off the rails, the deadline was coming up. I saw all the signs of the preparatory blame game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Move Toward Your Dream</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/move-toward-your-dream/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/move-toward-your-dream/</guid>
      <description>Ready? Set? Go!
To get to finish, you first need to start! More importantly, keep going!
I look at each day that I get up as a leg in a race that goes on and on. Hopefully each day ends in the dial being moved towards my dream. Some days I make great progress and I feel like I am running on air, some days it is more like pulling myself out of the mud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Procrastination Is The Antidote</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/procrastination-antidote/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/procrastination-antidote/</guid>
      <description>Procrastination. This word embodies many parts of how I conduct my day. Getting started on actual work is hard for me. However, when it is something I believe is valuable, I jump into it with vigor and resolve as long as I can see the end of it. Otherwise, I become apathetic to the very thought of engagement. When I procrastinate on the premium, that is where the problem occurs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Traits I Am Building</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/network-traits-i-am-building/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/network-traits-i-am-building/</guid>
      <description>The railways remind me of one of the most intricate networks that built our country. There is a lot we can learn from the planning that went into it.
My network is personal. I intentionally look for the right people to succeed with me. They are people of integrity, high value, and share in the passions of my heart. The work ahead is embraced with perseverance by these leaders of many and servants of all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choose Necessary Over Uncomfortable</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/choose-necessary-uncomfortable/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/choose-necessary-uncomfortable/</guid>
      <description>Make sure that you watch out for the warning signs of being too comfortable.
I have been wearing eye glasses since I was a kid. They were the thick kind, with prisms and everything. I would break them, throw them, scratch them, and lose them all the time. I learned to compensate without them, one eye becoming weaker, the other more tired as it was being used more. I was never comfortable with wearing glasses early in my life, but now necessity has me wearing progressive bifocals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attracting a Team to Achieve A Dream</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/achieve-a-dream/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/achieve-a-dream/</guid>
      <description>Each of us has a dream. For many of us it is tucked inside our hearts and minds. For others, the dream is at the forefront of their lives. Some have already started working on their dream to make it a reality. The fantastic idea, the futuristic vision, and the passion to solve a need must have a team greater than 1.
It takes a team working together to pull across the finish line</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking Credit is Really Stealing</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/credit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/credit/</guid>
      <description>Teams from over 80 countries competed. No individuals allowed
The project was a smashing success. John went up to receive the award that was given out at the company meeting. The applause was great and people were thrilled with the completion of such a complex project full of intricacies. This is the type of work that brought the company together. However, the people on his team were not cheering, but rather bitter and angry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What do you want to accomplish?</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/accomplish/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/accomplish/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How many times have you heard the statement, &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know where to begin?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Memories For Others</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/create-memories-for-others/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/create-memories-for-others/</guid>
      <description>There are few things more enjoyable than looking back on a specific memory in your life. The one I remember most vividly is when my brother and I would go out and play golf with our grandfather. We rarely swung a club, but were rather foragers in the rough and creeks for lost golf balls. I remember the tin cup my grandfather would break out that we would dip into the creek and the sour ball candy we would get on the third and sixth holes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Abundant Mindset</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/an-abundant-mindset/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/an-abundant-mindset/</guid>
      <description>Some of my favorite books growing up were encyclopedias. I remember looking at the 26 volumes and thinking about how the whole world was captured there. Jump forward 30+ years. Things have sure changed on what information is at our fingertips. But information is not knowledge, and by itself, the value is small. Combine information with our ability to think, understand, and act on it and the world can be changed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doors of Opportunity Await</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/door-of-opportunity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/door-of-opportunity/</guid>
      <description>A joyous day for my daughter. Happy Birthday!
Today is a beautiful day for my daughter. The world is opening a door of opportunity by officially recognizing her as an adult. As a parent, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t be more proud to see the growth and maturity just blossom. I do believe there are few things in life that have such an impact as the recognition of adulthood. Along with the recognition comes a new sense of adventure, a new definition of responsibility, and an acute awareness of independence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Cooperate or Compete</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/to-cooperate-or-compete/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/to-cooperate-or-compete/</guid>
      <description>Think of the cooperation that it took to build this bridge across the water!
We are taught from a young age how to cooperate with others to create a more harmonious environment. We are also taught how to compete with the premise that it will make us better human beings. Cooperation is a behavior that benefits others through working together to achieve something greater. Competition builds the character of an individual for self-growth and gain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pursuit is the True Reward</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/pursuit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/pursuit/</guid>
      <description>When you dream big, everything that pertains to the dream is big.
You will have to make big decisions. You will have to take big risks. You will have big disappointments. You will potentially get the big reward you envisions. Take a little time on the path to accomplish your dream to reflect. Captured in the garden of the Peterhoff Palace in St. Petersburg.
The first 3 bullets describe what will happen if you pursue your dream.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change Happens Constantly</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/change-happens-constantly/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/change-happens-constantly/</guid>
      <description>You don&amp;rsquo;t like your work situation? Is your marriage unsatisfying? Is your life not where you want it to be? What is common about these three questions? You are. Each one of these questions can also have one answer which is &amp;ldquo;Change yourself.&amp;rdquo; By reflecting on all the things that are negative, you may be able to see patterns that are inside you or an element of your life that you would like to change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Will You Invest in Today?</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/who-will-you-invest-in-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/who-will-you-invest-in-today/</guid>
      <description>I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize it for many years, but Robert chose to invest in me. It is now 20+ years later and I still think about how he was feeding me wisdom, knowledge, and instruction about how to live a life with integrity and thankfulness. In the time I spent working for Robert, I believe each encounter was a lesson in life that he wanted to impart. We have lost touch over the years, because I didn&amp;rsquo;t understand the value of his mentorship and friendship.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop Calendar Abuse</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/stop-calendar-abuse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/stop-calendar-abuse/</guid>
      <description>Look&#39;s like a busy month in 1978. original file at https://silverlaughterband.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/1978-07calendar.jpg
Let&amp;rsquo;s start by saying I dislike calendars. They are reminders of all the work that I &amp;ldquo;think&amp;rdquo; I have to do. Until recently. In the past I have been fighting the battle of appointment Monday, where I start the week with a clean slate and by the end of the day on Monday, I have a calendar 80% full of meetings that I don&amp;rsquo;t want to attend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Life is an Artistic Masterpiece</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/your-life-is-an-artistic-masterpiece/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/your-life-is-an-artistic-masterpiece/</guid>
      <description>God has given you all the tools to create your masterpiece. By the choices you have made so far and by the decisions of the future a masterpiece will be produced. It may be a precision sculpture, or an abstract painting, or even an epic that chronicles your life. The cool things about masterpieces is that they are one of a kind and cannot be duplicated. They capture emotion, display truth, and create impressions on those who view your masterpiece.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Purpose with 3 Questions</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/finding-purpose/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/finding-purpose/</guid>
      <description>John Maxwell&amp;rsquo;s 30 day journey has really been a great inspiration for me. This post is actually my reflection on 3 questions he asks us to internalize. The combination of these questions were powerful for me to getting a definition around significance and how to be intentional. I am realizing that I can take charge of being the author of my life only when I become clear in what it is that I am supposed to be doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Think Before Acting</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/think-before-acting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/think-before-acting/</guid>
      <description>One of the most exciting parts of my job tackling tough problems to come up with great solutions. While the journey can be difficult at times, I know that the reward of a job well done outweighs any challenges, risks, or disappointments that will occur along the way. The most valuable lesson I have learned is to think before acting on any decision. Thinking deeply about your upcoming actions prepares you for the twists and turns on the journey to a solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Success For Others Is In Your Control</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/others-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/others-success/</guid>
      <description>We are standing on the shoulders of giants for every success. Each day this reality becomes more clear for me. What is so funny though is the giants we recognize today are just ordinary people doing extraordinary things for others. I know that my success is directly related to those people who give me a boost in the process.
My wife is one of the strongest contributors to my success.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encouragement is contagious</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/encouragement-is-contagious/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/encouragement-is-contagious/</guid>
      <description>Encouragement is a gift that everyone can give. It soothes the soul, lifts up the spirit, and builds confidence to accomplish great things. Words of encouragement and random acts of kindness are actionable ways to show appreciation. Too often, we miss great opportunities to pour a few kind words into someone&amp;rsquo;s life.
I think eulogies are wasted on the dead. It’s the living who need to hear kind words spoken about them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listen Intently, Listen Deeply</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/listen-intently-listen-deeply/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/listen-intently-listen-deeply/</guid>
      <description>Most of you have heard how grown-ups talk in Peanuts movies, &amp;ldquo;Mwahmwahmwah, wah wah mwah&amp;rdquo;. I must confess that on occasions, I hear those same types of sounds when others are talking to me. I am distracted and fail to listen with intention. Other times, I only get the surface of the conversation, but don&amp;rsquo;t listen to the true meaning and diagnose the root message of what the person is really trying to say.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A More Personalized Greeting</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/a-more-personalized-greeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/a-more-personalized-greeting/</guid>
      <description>Welcome board at the Imagine Cup
Monday mornings when you go into work, has one of your coworkers asked: &amp;ldquo;How was your weekend?&amp;rdquo; I know I greet people like this pretty often. However, what I have lately come to realize that this question is just a formality. It is a question said in passing. I don&amp;rsquo;t take the time to listen. The insincerity is front and center and people recognize it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intentional Living, A New Way Of Life</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/intentional-living-a-new-way-of-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/intentional-living-a-new-way-of-life/</guid>
      <description>The dam is a great example of an idea becoming intentional
It is nine o&amp;rsquo;clock tonight on November 1st. About a week ago, I started pondering the idea of writing a blog post a day for the month of November, kind of like a NaNoWriMo challenge. I found other things to do today to not get started. First, I didn&amp;rsquo;t take advantage of my morning and before I knew it, we were on our way to church.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let me tell you about the WORD I know</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/the-word-i-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/the-word-i-know/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear Friend,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to share with you something incredible, something life changing, something mind blowing.  It is the WORD. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating an Identity Seed Value</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/updating-an-identity-seed-value/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/updating-an-identity-seed-value/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently ran into an issue, where I had to mix environments while developing.  On top of the mixed environments, I was manipulating data. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Focus Will Bring Great Results</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/focus-great-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/focus-great-results/</guid>
      <description>Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be nice if all you had to say was &amp;ldquo;Focus&amp;rdquo; and everything just fell into place for the rest of the day? Do you feel that your day spins out of control as you get randomized? If you stray from a normal routine, do you frequently feel that something was missed? I have seen that great focus leads to great results.
Short Term Focus Yesterday was a totally randomizing day, constant interruptions combined with a lack of resolve to &amp;ldquo;start&amp;rdquo; anything that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t result in completion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living a Transformational Life</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/living-a-transformational-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/living-a-transformational-life/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I have tried to take a step back and look at the transformations that are occurring all around me. I am seeing my seventeen year old now as a young adult making choices for herself, that used to be part of our role as parents. At work, I see the decisions of last years organizational shifts starting to solidify. I look in the mirror and see the grey hairs of wisdom where youthful ignorance used to be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Cleaning at Work</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/spring-cleaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/spring-cleaning/</guid>
      <description>Spring is upon us. The sun is shining, my wife saw a hummingbird at the feeder the other day, and the tulip fields are in full bloom. Now is the time for that annual endeavor called Spring Cleaning. You know what I am talking about. Look around for the &amp;ldquo;junk&amp;rdquo; that is building up, open the windows to let fresh air in, and scrub away the dreariness that was winter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cost of Perfection Is Higher Than You Think</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/value-perfection-higher-think/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/value-perfection-higher-think/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I was in a conversation about the cost of getting a specification to a &amp;ldquo;perfect&amp;rdquo; state. I made a bold statement that most times perfection has too high of a cost and that I just need good enough. After stating that I started to consider what &amp;ldquo;good enough&amp;rdquo; really means.
What is &amp;ldquo;Good Enough&amp;rdquo; Good enough has the appropriate quality that meets the needs of the task. For NASA, it may be down to the micrometer Good enough enables the customer/individual to do the task with a high level of satisfaction that doesn&amp;rsquo;t frustrate them Good enough drives higher throughput Good enough can be iterated on What Perfection Costs Time to market - Perfection may have you missing the train Stress - Perfection always has complications that add tension Strategic thinking - Perfection gets to deep tactical execution which distracts from strategic initiatives Resources Michael Hyatt just posted a fantastic article about &amp;ldquo;Perfectionism&amp;rdquo; that covers a lot of this same theme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Personal Scorecard</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/building-personal-scorecard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/building-personal-scorecard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A local radio show this morning was having a conversation about using a scorecard for children&amp;rsquo;s behavior for parents. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Danger in Isolation</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/danger-isolation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/danger-isolation/</guid>
      <description>Some call it JOB SECURITY. Others call protecting intellectual property. Many want to just have the end result perfect before sharing out. There is danger in these ideas and thoughts as they lead to isolationist principles. When we break down isolation in the workplace, many times this is due to self-serving / self-preserving attitudes. Individuals see benefits to this as it provides a perception of worth and security that sometimes is lacking in their jobs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watch Your Tone When Listening</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/watch-tone-listening/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/watch-tone-listening/</guid>
      <description>My face said it all. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t paying attention. How soon can they be finished with their monologue of discontent and discouragement. Lately, I have been observing characteristics of others as they listen or attempt to. Whether it is a meeting or a 1:1 conversation, we all may need to do a little self reflection or at least pretend that someone is recording us. Here are some of the latest visual queues of poor listening that I have seen:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work is what you make it - 10 observations</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/work-is-what-you-make-it-10-observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/work-is-what-you-make-it-10-observations/</guid>
      <description>I was really looking forward to a breakfast talk about work and worship in downtown Seattle. The cogs of the work engine were grinding and a pleasant change of pace where I could soak in information was just what I needed. I am glad I wasn&amp;rsquo;t disappointed. Here are 10 key notes in no particular order from that talk:
Very few people ever get to work in what they are truly passionate about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Call Is Not Private</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/the-call-is-not-private/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/the-call-is-not-private/</guid>
      <description>I am in hot water with my conscience.
Don&amp;rsquo;t ever think that you are just talking to a single person over Skype, Lync, or other online meeting communications and that the conversation is private. As a matter of fact don&amp;rsquo;t even think that an email is private. I am doing a lot of reflecting on this today, as I participated as a listener in a call without being announced. My conscience bothered me all night and honestly, I didn&amp;rsquo;t measure up to the ethics and morals that I strongly believe in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowerment During Change Series:  Leading by Serving</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/leading-by-serving/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/leading-by-serving/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Everyone must serve somebody, even if it is yourself. As employees, we server our managers or company. As a husband I serve my family.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowerment During Change Series:  Leading by Liberating</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/liberating/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/liberating/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is almost a certainty that you and the company that you work for will go through a major change. With every change comes fear, doubt, tension, uncertainty, and anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embracing Culture Change is a Choice: Leaders can make it easier</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/embracing-culture-change-is-a-choice-leaders-can-make-it-easier/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/embracing-culture-change-is-a-choice-leaders-can-make-it-easier/</guid>
      <description>Did you get that memo about shifting the way we work? Have you heard about how the company is focusing in on one mission in the halls? Are you all in to make a difference for a better workplace? Is your answer maybe, or I&amp;rsquo;ll believe it when I see it? If so you are not alone. Changing a culture is a monumental effort that takes the very essence of what we are today and breaks us with the intent of rebuilding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leaders Create A Harbor</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/leaders-create-a-harbor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/leaders-create-a-harbor/</guid>
      <description>Friday Harbor - With a set of rainbows!
The storms of work are always around us and can flare up at any time from any direction. In our jobs, hopefully there are sunny warm days with only a few scattered showers. Every so often though we hear the call for &amp;ldquo;man overboard&amp;rdquo; or feel the waves filled with pressure crashing in on us. We become overwhelmed, distraught, anxious, and stressed over our work situation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Negotiated The Price</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/you-negotiated-the-price/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/you-negotiated-the-price/</guid>
      <description>I hate to admit that I often have felt treated unfairly by my leaders and management. Recently, another person was chosen to attend a meeting that I was clearly entitled to be at, because of course I was the best person to represent. Why would my manager do this to me? Doesn&amp;rsquo;t she know the value that I could have provided the best insight and value? Pretty arrogant right? I had to swallow my pride and ask for forgiveness.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
