<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>communication on Tribal Thirst</title>
    <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/tags/communication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in communication on Tribal Thirst</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.tribalthirst.com/tags/communication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Setting Expectations for Communications Responses</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/communications-responses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/communications-responses/</guid>
      <description>As I have started thinking about the best ways to communicate, I am realizing that most of my communications problems are self-inflicted. One of the biggest areas is how I respond. I very rarely respond to text messages, I may read Facebook feeds every couple of days, I am not consistent on mediums such as twitter, and I am too instantaneous on email.
Last week&#39;s email statistics via Delve Analytics</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Provide Context for the Data</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/data-context/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/data-context/</guid>
      <description>Just a bunch of information that makes no sense. Just like many decks I see with charts.
I am often asked to provide charts of data, tables of information, and bullet point lists though the week. I just put together a basic bar chart in Excel (Select your table and hit the F11 key) a few hours ago. Today&amp;rsquo;s topic in communication is making sure that the data meets the context of how it is being used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting Communications</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/meeting-communications/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/meeting-communications/</guid>
      <description>I am glad these guys were at the meeting. Mural on board the Pride of America
As I was reviewing the email for the last time in the day, I received four meeting requests, all with no agenda and ambiguous titles. My initial response was to just decline without any reason. After a hard pause, I decided to be more civilized fashion and at least respond with a couple of questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Non-Verbal Communication Matters</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/non-verbal-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/non-verbal-communication/</guid>
      <description>One day I received feedback after a meeting took place. My manager graciously let me know that my opinions on various topics were well communicated. There was only one problem, I didn&amp;rsquo;t say a word. My body language, facial expressions, and the way I made eye contact with others was truly transparent and exposed for all to see. I constantly have to work in meetings to make sure that my non-verbal cues are appropriate for the time and location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 5 W&#39;s of Giving Feedback</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/the-5-ws-of-giving-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/the-5-ws-of-giving-feedback/</guid>
      <description>Feedback is something that shouldn&#39;t be frosty or cold. It should always be tempered with warmth.
I am a person who is always looking for feedback, constructive criticism, and critique about my life, work, and abilities. This keeps me humble to grow, hungry to learn, and happy when the feedback helps. On the flipside, I am not shy about giving back in these mediums to others. I have distilled some core truths into the 5 W&amp;rsquo;s that must happen for the information one shares to be effective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Purpose Of Feedback</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/defining-purpose/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/defining-purpose/</guid>
      <description>Think of the purpose that this chandelier was made with. Alexandrinsky Theater, St. Petersburg, Russia This was a poem I created a couple of years back around how we shape purpose in our lives. Feedback becomes an essential component. In the last few months, I really have been focused on getting clarity of purpose and have shared a lot of my thoughts to garner feedback. It has been a very healthy and productive exercise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communicate Your Vision (Updated)</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/communicate-your-vision/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/communicate-your-vision/</guid>
      <description>As with any vision statement, it is a grand view. Horseshoe Canyon in Moab.
When was the last time you looked at the Vision, Mission, and Values of your company? Maybe you have them memorized and they come out in every part of your being. If so quit reading now. For the other 99.9999% of us keep reading as the vision definitely needs focused on.
Dusting off the vision statement Read the most recent company vision statement.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
