<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>leadership on Tribal Thirst</title>
    <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/categories/leadership/</link>
    <description>Recent content in leadership on Tribal Thirst</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.tribalthirst.com/categories/leadership/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Setting Boundaries as Leaders and Employees</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/setting-boundaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/setting-boundaries/</guid>
      <description>Do you know a leader who says yes to everything? Their team just finished a significant and stressful month to get an &amp;ldquo;urgent&amp;rdquo; marketing experience out the door and the leader agreed to deliver something else urgent on a compressed timeline. Where was the boundary between the finish and start of the next project. It never materialized. Take a more concrete example. Do you ever block time off on your calendar to get work done and people just schedule right over that without any care or thought?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communicate Your Vision (Updated)</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/communicate-your-vision/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/communicate-your-vision/</guid>
      <description>As with any vision statement, it is a grand view. Horseshoe Canyon in Moab.
When was the last time you looked at the Vision, Mission, and Values of your company? Maybe you have them memorized and they come out in every part of your being. If so quit reading now. For the other 99.9999% of us keep reading as the vision definitely needs focused on.
Dusting off the vision statement Read the most recent company vision statement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Focus Will Bring Great Results</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/focus-great-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/focus-great-results/</guid>
      <description>Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be nice if all you had to say was &amp;ldquo;Focus&amp;rdquo; and everything just fell into place for the rest of the day? Do you feel that your day spins out of control as you get randomized? If you stray from a normal routine, do you frequently feel that something was missed? I have seen that great focus leads to great results.
Short Term Focus Yesterday was a totally randomizing day, constant interruptions combined with a lack of resolve to &amp;ldquo;start&amp;rdquo; anything that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t result in completion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Cleaning at Work</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/spring-cleaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/spring-cleaning/</guid>
      <description>Spring is upon us. The sun is shining, my wife saw a hummingbird at the feeder the other day, and the tulip fields are in full bloom. Now is the time for that annual endeavor called Spring Cleaning. You know what I am talking about. Look around for the &amp;ldquo;junk&amp;rdquo; that is building up, open the windows to let fresh air in, and scrub away the dreariness that was winter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cost of Perfection Is Higher Than You Think</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/value-perfection-higher-think/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/value-perfection-higher-think/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I was in a conversation about the cost of getting a specification to a &amp;ldquo;perfect&amp;rdquo; state. I made a bold statement that most times perfection has too high of a cost and that I just need good enough. After stating that I started to consider what &amp;ldquo;good enough&amp;rdquo; really means.
What is &amp;ldquo;Good Enough&amp;rdquo; Good enough has the appropriate quality that meets the needs of the task. For NASA, it may be down to the micrometer Good enough enables the customer/individual to do the task with a high level of satisfaction that doesn&amp;rsquo;t frustrate them Good enough drives higher throughput Good enough can be iterated on What Perfection Costs Time to market - Perfection may have you missing the train Stress - Perfection always has complications that add tension Strategic thinking - Perfection gets to deep tactical execution which distracts from strategic initiatives Resources Michael Hyatt just posted a fantastic article about &amp;ldquo;Perfectionism&amp;rdquo; that covers a lot of this same theme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Personal Scorecard</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/building-personal-scorecard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/building-personal-scorecard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A local radio show this morning was having a conversation about using a scorecard for children&amp;rsquo;s behavior for parents. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowerment During Change Series:  Leading by Serving</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/leading-by-serving/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/leading-by-serving/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Everyone must serve somebody, even if it is yourself. As employees, we server our managers or company. As a husband I serve my family.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowerment During Change Series:  Leading by Liberating</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/liberating/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/liberating/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is almost a certainty that you and the company that you work for will go through a major change. With every change comes fear, doubt, tension, uncertainty, and anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embracing Culture Change is a Choice: Leaders can make it easier</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/embracing-culture-change-is-a-choice-leaders-can-make-it-easier/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/embracing-culture-change-is-a-choice-leaders-can-make-it-easier/</guid>
      <description>Did you get that memo about shifting the way we work? Have you heard about how the company is focusing in on one mission in the halls? Are you all in to make a difference for a better workplace? Is your answer maybe, or I&amp;rsquo;ll believe it when I see it? If so you are not alone. Changing a culture is a monumental effort that takes the very essence of what we are today and breaks us with the intent of rebuilding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leaders Create A Harbor</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/leaders-create-a-harbor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/leaders-create-a-harbor/</guid>
      <description>Friday Harbor - With a set of rainbows!
The storms of work are always around us and can flare up at any time from any direction. In our jobs, hopefully there are sunny warm days with only a few scattered showers. Every so often though we hear the call for &amp;ldquo;man overboard&amp;rdquo; or feel the waves filled with pressure crashing in on us. We become overwhelmed, distraught, anxious, and stressed over our work situation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Negotiated The Price</title>
      <link>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/you-negotiated-the-price/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tribalthirst.com/posts/you-negotiated-the-price/</guid>
      <description>I hate to admit that I often have felt treated unfairly by my leaders and management. Recently, another person was chosen to attend a meeting that I was clearly entitled to be at, because of course I was the best person to represent. Why would my manager do this to me? Doesn&amp;rsquo;t she know the value that I could have provided the best insight and value? Pretty arrogant right? I had to swallow my pride and ask for forgiveness.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
